Guide to the Creighton Lacy Papers, 1952-1988
Duke University. University Archives
Creighton Lacy papers 1952-1988
Duke University. University Archives
Lacy, Creighton, 1919-.
1 linear feet Extent: 1000 Items
Creighton Lacy has seved as a professor at Duke University Divinity School since 1953. The collection contains correspondence, reports, sermons, directories, memoranda, printed matter and clippings.
UA.29.02.0098
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
Provenance
The Creighton Lacy Papers were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1988-1989, 1998.
Biographical Note
Creighton Lacy was born in China in 1919. He received his A. B. (summa cum laude) at Swarthmore College, his B. D. (magna cum laude), Yale University Divinity School, and his Ph.D. from Yale University. He began teaching in the Divinity School in 1953 and was Professor of World Christianity at Duke University Divinity School. As of 1991, he is a Professor Emeritus of Parish Ministry at Duke University Divinity School.
Collection Overview
The collection contains correspondence, reports, sermons, directories, memoranda, printed matter and clippings. The papers include programs for the annual Symposium on Christian Missions sponsored by the Divinity school and its Missions Committee. There are several folders on Duke alumni who were active in the missions of the Methodist and other churches, particularly those in the Far East. Also included are manuscripts, memoranda, and clippings concerning the Nixon Library controversy of 1981, a civil rights sit-in at Watts Grill in Chapel Hill in 1964 and clippings and newspapers about student unrest at Duke and other campuses between 1968-1970.
Subject Headings
Baptist Church. Southern Baptist Convention -- Missions; Civil rights demonstrations -- North Carolina -- Chapel Hill -- 1964; Duke University. Divinity School -- Alumni; Duke University. Divinity School-Lectures, seminars, etc. -- Symposium on Christian Missions, 1958; Lacy, Creighton, 1919-; Methodist Church (U.S.) -- Missions
Contents of Collection
- Container List, 2 Boxes
  - Correspondence (folder 1) (Box 1)
  - Correspondence (folder 2) (Box 1)
  - Correspondence (folder 3) (Box 1)
  - Divinity School Alumni-Missionaries (folder 4) (Box 1)
  - Divinity School Alumni-Missionaries (folder 5) (Box 1)
  - Faculty Executive Council, 1970- (folder 6) (Box 1)
  - Missions Committee, 1956-1971 (folder 7) (Box 1)
  - Divinity School Alumni-Missionaries (folder 8) (Box 1)
  - Nix on Nixon, 1981 (Box 2)
  - Mission Symposium, 1952-1957 (Box 2)
  - Mission Symposium, 1958-1962 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous Services and Speeches (Box 2)
  - Sit-in News clippings and Trial Notes, 1961-1966 (Box 2)